Guide to the Professional and Administrative Staff Association (PASTA) of the Museum of Modern Art Records WAG.174
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Professional and Administrative Staff Association (PASTA) of the Museum of Modern Art Records
1960-2000
1970-1986
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Professional and Administrative Staff Association of the Museum of Modern Art
Gray, John
WAG.174
17 Linear Feet in 10 record cartons, 12 manuscript boxes, 2 half manuscript boxes, and 2 oversize folders.
2 audiocassettes
The Profession and Administrative Staff Association (PASTA) at the Museum Modern Art was the first union of museum professionals in the United States and is now affiliated with UAW Local 2110. This collection contains meeting minutes, negotiation documents and contracts, grievances, leaflets, committee files, and strike materials.
Scope and Contents
The majority of this collection consists of committee files, negotiation documents, press, and strike materials. Materials include: memos; correspondence; flyers; reports; financial documents; election nominations, notices, and ballots; meeting minutes, agendas, and notices; newspaper clippings; press releases; newsletters; demand letters; research files (e.g. on health care, family leave, education, etc.); agreement drafts; contract proposals and offers; audiocassette tapes; bargaining session notes; questionnaires and surveys regarding salary, issues, and priorities; grievances and arbitrations; rally songs; strike leaflets; and photographic prints, negatives, and contact sheets.
Historical Note
The Profession and Administrative Staff Association (PASTA) at the Museum Modern Art (MOMA) began in response to discrepancies in salaries and concerns regarding job security held by individuals working at MOMA. In 1971, PASTA held elections and officially affiliated with the Distributive Workers of America, as Museum Local No. 1. This was the first union of museum professionals in the United States. PASTA established an affiliation with United Auto Workers (UAW), District 65 in 1980 and is now affiliated with UAW Local 2110. PASTA conducted a strike in 2000 during contract negotiations before MOMA's 2001-2004 expansion project.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. Materials are in the order in which they were received from the donor.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by the Professional and Administrative Staff Association (PASTA) of the Museum of Modern Art in 1996. The accession number 1996.020 is associated with this gift. Additional materials were donated by John Gray in 2001. The accession number NPA.2001.084 is associated with these materials.
The accession number NPA.2005.074 is also associated with this collection.
Labor unions -- New York (State) -- New York.; Strikes and lockouts -- New York (State) -- New York.; Collective bargaining -- New York (State) -- New York.; Grievance arbitration.; Arbitration (Administrative law); Arbitration and award.; Minutes (administrative records).; Contracts.; Collective labor agreements.; Museums -- Employees -- United States; Museum of Modern Art (New York, N.Y.); Professional and Administrative Staff Association of the Museum of Modern Art; Professional and Administrative Staff Association of the Museum of Modern Art; Gray, John; Museum Workers Union of America; United Automobile, Aircraft, and Vehicle Workers of America. District 65
- Negotiations materials; Committee and administrative files; Press; Photographic prints of strikes, 1976-1985 (Box 1)
- Negotiations materials; Committee files; Strike materials; Press; Photographic contact sheets, 1972-1988 (Box 2)
- Committee and administrative files; Negotiations materials; Press; Rally and picketing materials, 1964-1973 (Box 3, Box 17)
- Committee materials; Press; Research files; Photographic prints and contact sheets of strikes, 1960, 1969-1987 (Box 4)
- Committee files (including Exhibition Committee events and photographic prints); Financial documents; Negotiations materials; Press, 1970-1986 (Box 5, Box 18)
- Negotiations materials; Petitions and letters of support; Press; Administrative materials; Committee files, 1968-1982 (Box 6, Box 19, Box 20, Box 21)
- Committee files and negotiations materials, 1983-1991 (Box 7, Box 22)
- Negotiations materials; Committee files; Press, 1977, 1981-1988 (Box 8)
- Committee files; Negotiations materials; Strike materials (including press and photographic negatives), 1973, 1983-1994 (Box 9)
- Grievances and arbitrations; Administrative materials; Strike materials; Press; Negotiations materials; Financial documents, 1982-1996 (Box 10, Box 23)
- Grievances; Negotiations materials; Press; Committee files, 1960-1975 (Box 11, Box 24)
- Committee files; Negotiations materials; Press; Elections materials; Financial documents, 1970-1984 (Box 12)
- Grievances; Press; Financial documents; Negotiations materials, 1971-1985 (Box 13)
- Administrative and committee files; Strike materials (including photographic prints); Press; Negotiations Materials, 1970-1980, 1985-1996, 2000 (Box 14)
- Grievances; Committee files; Administrative materials, 1970-1991 (Box 15, Box 16)
- Audiovisual Material – WBAI PASTA Negotiation, 1987 (Box Shared Tamiment 067)
- Audiovisual Material – Joan Saunders on Radio Talking about the Settlement, 1987 (Box Shared Tamiment 067)